Contact

ryancarolina88@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/r0bothead (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Java

Troubleshooting

Game Development

Certifications

CTFL

IWATSU VoIP

Certified SAFe® 4 Agilist

Honors-Awards

Highest Scholastic Average in Ordnance School Graduating Class, NATTC Pensacola FL.

Ryan Conklin

Senior Software Test Engineer at EXPANSIA (Active TS/SCI) Charleston, South Carolina Area

Summary

I want to start off by saying I love this work. Technology is my passion and when I take interest in something I consume all the subject matter I can get my hands on. I work until I'm able to teach and write tutorials of my own on whatever is dominating my time.

Eat. Sleep. Build. Repeat.

I have extensive experience with many different technical platforms. From design, development, and testing, I have worked in various fields. Among these are positions like game design and development, QA engineer, software development engineer in test, VoIP administration, and web application development. I look forward to my next challenge, examples of my work and references upon request.

What currently has my attention:

Infrastructure as code, configuration as code, and policy as code. How tools like Terraform give us the power to use ALL of the cloud and not just a single provider. Finally, how QA will write tests in a spiffy automated way that will exercise and assert these distributed systems that are fully built in code and live in the cloud. Writing tests at the application level no longer provides the coverage development teams need. Chaos engineering and test coverage at the IaC level is quickly becoming the new standard!

Experience

EXPANSIA
Senior Software Test Engineer
October 2018 - Present
Charleston, South Carolina

Currently, I am building a test framework to integrate into a newly developed CI/CD pipeline that will be used to build and test various AMI, VMs, or other infrastructure as code artifacts. My framework is designed to test at the IaC, Policy as code, and application level using tools like Terraform, Terratest, and Sentinel. The framework is built on Selenium/WebDriver written in Java and also leverages Ranorex(.NET) for UI/functional tests. Orchestration along with test builds and result reporting is handled by Jenkins, which produces a test results report via surefire in XML for easy consumption by the development team.

Other tasks include daily scrum and the development of technical documentation for the current test framework and test tools. Building vm's via ESXi, hardening with puppet, and maintaining git/SCM repositories.

Ceterus, Inc.

Senior Software Development Engineer Test October 2016 - October 2018 (2 years 1 month)

Charleston, South Carolina Area

I am building out an automated test framework designed to test the Ceterus Edge application, which follows the distributed application architecture. The framework is written in Java and makes use of Selenium, webDriver, RESTassured, OpenCSV and several other libraries to help the QA team provide test coverage at the UI, API, and database layers. The framework is a modular design which allows easy scaling and test maintenance. Assertions are performed using JUnit and Hamcrest matchers. The tests are run during each deployment of code to the QA environment. My team uses Jenkins and we follow a CI/CD workflow, making several deployments a day. My test results are captured and made available in our team QA Slack channel. Our cross-browser, OS, and device testing is all handled through Sauce Labs, which is integrated with the test framework. When I am not working on the framework, I am helping other QA team members with producing test plans, refining requirements, and training on writing automated tests using the Ceterus test automation framework.

SPARC, LLC Lead QA Engineer July 2014 - October 2016 (2 years 4 months)

I work on the US Postal team and my responsibilities include writing test automation code, QA of all finished modules, and design/development of test automation tools.

I have built automation tools using components like SOAPUI, powered by groovy scripts and the SOAPUI Maven plugin. This allows my team to kick off SOAP tests using maven jobs within our Jenkins server. This environment gives me the ability to create custom automation, such as nightly regression tests. Providing my team with more test coverage, but reducing the time to create useful tests.

Currently I am working on using machine learning to analyze past defect data to create defect aggregation patterns. I then hope to use this pattern data to create defect "heat maps" of our development projects, which in turn will help focus future regression tests and the development of new test frameworks. This should reduce "pesticide paradox", time spent "guessing" which modules to test, and overall budget spent on testing.

Blue Acorn QA Specialist January 2014 - August 2014 (8 months)

I worked within the LAMP stack, testing all modules and Magento site changes using manual and automated testing. Using tools like Selenium web driver, node.js, and mocha, I wrote test plans to verify user checkout process, payment processing, and shopping cart functionality.

CharlestonGamer.com
Game Designer/Community Manager
October 2013 - 2014 (1 year 3 months)

Working with a super passionate team, I was tasked with character and game concept prototyping. I worked closely with the art and engineering team to quickly build out concepts for proposed projects.

Most of my work consisted of game systems design, game documentation, and level design/scripting in Unity 3D.

The Angelo Group, Inc.
Game Designer
June 2013 - October 2013 (5 months)

I worked with art, engineering, and design departments to maintain focus and scope on various game projects. As a secondary task I worked in engineering as a developer, working mostly on the development of the 2D retro title "Undermine".

Atomic Blue

Intern - Prospect

February 2013 - June 2013 (5 months)

My tasks included learning the game, lore, quest chain system, skill development system, combat system, and "bug" hunting.

Pixel Block Party

Game Designer

February 2012 - June 2013 (1 year 5 months)

Summerville, South Carolina

Game designer/developer.

eTrak-plus

Software QA/Tester

June 2012 - December 2012 (7 months)

Defect tracking and replication along with daily testing of hot fixes, new builds, and new features. After 4 months I also started helping with the java development as well. Working on getting the web application to a state in which it could be replicated across 4 tomcat servers. A secondary task was the gamification of the eTrak application. As we wanted our users to have their eTrack use integrated with social media sites.

JK Harris & Company

IT System Analyst

October 2010 - September 2011 (1 year)

Goose Creek, South Carolina

Manage VoIP and telecoms along with supporting the office imaging hardware. Secondary task included helping with trouble tickets and break/fix tickets.

Perot Systems

Desktop Support Analyst

June 2009 - October 2010 (1 year 5 months)

Assist in the imaging and deployment of dell desktops and dell laptops. Trouble shooting any and all issues that users may encounter during the deployment and after. Support the 1000+ users from Boeing, Vought, and Global Aeronautica.

Central Electric Supply
Help Desk/Network Support
November 2008 - March 2009 (5 months)

Support of 500+ CES branch stores, over 1000+ users. Support users with trouble shooting desktop, laptop, Thin client(Wyse terminals) hardware/ software, network connection, malware, IMS SQL Database, Printer/scanner/ fax connection & setup, and VoIP phone issues (Shore Tel).

Black Tie Technology Computer/IT Services May 2008 - November 2008 (7 months)

IT trouble shooting windows based computers, software upgrades and sales, hardware upgrades and sales, customer service calls/visits, Computer sales, small home/business network setup/repair, data recovery.

US Navy

Petty Officer 3rd Class, Aviation Ordnance September 2003 - September 2007 (4 years 1 month)

Build, service, and/or destroy all major ordnance types for the US Navy. Specialized in the ordnance for the F/A-18 Super Hornet.

Education

Full Sail University

Bachelor of Science (BS), Game and Interactive Media Design · (2011 - 2014)